Jordan Rhodes

9967 Blackbird Cir Highlands Ranch, CO 80130 **813.701.4126**

email: jsrhodes15@hey.com

personal website: https://jordansrhodes.com

Professional Summary

I am a highly driven software engineer with an insatiable hunger for knowledge, who is able to add value to every project I am part of. I have spent the last few years working in full-stack JavaScript land, focusing on React and Node.js. One of my biggest strengths is the knowledge and acceptance of my weaknesses. I am constantly working on my own projects to increase my knowledge and experience.

Technologies

Javascript ES6+ • React.js • Redux • Node • Express • Hapi • Docker • Kubernetes • Golang • Ruby on Rails • MongoDB • Postgres • Graphql • git • Heroku • AWS • Google Cloud Platform • Azure • HTML • CSS/SASS

Experience

FEBRUARY 2023 - Present

Edsights, New York - Senior Full Stack Developer

Technologies used: Nodejs, Vue, Django, Golang, Postgres, GCP

- Part of a small team of engineers developing a suite of products for higher education, focused on retention and student persistence.
- Joined as the team was planning a migration away from Django to Node and Go. During this
 time, we had to balance new feature development with resolving technical debt.
- Rewrote critical reports generation tool. Originally written in Python/Django, was taking almost 6 days to complete, and straining the database during this time. Evaluated options and chose Golang for speed. Refactored queries to allow for more CPU bound work, which alleviated the strain on the database.. After the rewrite, the reports now take around 1.5 hours.

APRIL 2018 - February 2023

Exzeo USA, Inc, Tampa - Senior Developer / Team Lead

Technologies used: Nodejs, React, Graphql, MongoDB, Docker, AWS

• Worked on a full-stack JS multi-tenant insurance management SAAS platform.

- Lead developer of a team that owns the front end of the platform. Building and maintaining a suite of apps, including a react-native iOS/Android application, used to manage book of business for various insurance products, as well as an admin application for managing consumers of the platform.
- Focused on dev and build infrastructure, code reuse between applications (front end and back end), vetting 3rd party libraries before use, building and maintaining a core library of reusable Javascript logic and React components focused on accessibility..
- Developed and spearheaded a highly successful program to mentor Junior/Entry-level engineers in order to broaden the hiring pool, with a specific goal of mine being to give entry level developers an opportunity to gain experience.
- Responsible for developing best practices around testing, including unit testing via react-testing-library/jest, integration testing with Cypress, and end to end testing using Selenium. Incorporated test suites in CI/CD pipeline.

OCTOBER 2016 - APRIL 2018

AgileThought, Tampa - JavaScript Developer

Technologies used: Nodejs, React, ASP.net, Azure, DocumentDB

- Made significant contributions on a very large greenfield project for a Big 4 accounting firm.
 The application was a cloud based, consuming an ASP.net Web API on Azure, using the 'Command Pattern' to fulfill REST requests to a collection of single page applications built with React.
- Started and helped to prove out a team focusing on reusable components which directly lead to increased velocity across all teams. Improved overall code quality, test coverage, and developer experience..
- Helped establish standards and core libraries to be used project and company wide. The
 main core library was a collection of React components to be consumed by other teams on
 the project with the explicit goal of writing the components in a manner that would not only
 be performant, but would serve as the basis for how to develop components in the project.

JUNE 2016 - OCTOBER 2016

Mercury New Media, Tampa - Developer Technician (Intern)

Technologies used: Nodejs, React, ReactNative, MongoDB

- Worked on Node.js and React.js full time. Pioneered React at the company, starting with a rewrite of an internal employee payroll application (originally written in Angular 1.x).
- Quickly became a vital part of a small team leading the company into full stack javascript development, allowing us to build products quickly with small teams.
- Owner of a full stack Javascript/React Native cross-platform eCommerce application.
 Wrote a RESTful Node.js API that was consumed by a React web app and React Native android / iOS applications. Hand-rolled user authentication and role based authorization, shopping cart, and admin area.

APRIL 2016 - JUNE 2016

WeVue, Tampa - Intern Ruby on Rails Developer

- Committed code throughout the stack on a Ruby on Rails application. Helped implement a
 web api that was consumed by android and iOS apps.
- Coordinated with product owners, designers, and other developers on multiple projects.
- Performed QA testing and developed QA scripts for both manual and automated testing.
- Created transactional email templates, wired up email service using SendGrid API.
- Coordinated QA and bug tracking between Rails, iOS, and Android teams.

MAY 2006 - JUNE 2016

Hospitality - Server

- Worked at various fine dining restaurants in the Tampa Bay area as a server / bartender
- Became a level 1 wine sommelier at Jackson's Bistro

Education

JANUARY 2006 - MAY 2007

Florida Institute of Technology, Melbourne, FL - Undergrad

Studied Engineering for two years while playing division 1AA baseball.

A Few Things I'm Proud Of

Personal Website

jordansrhodes.com

Personal website, mostly HTML and CSS, with some JavaScript modals. Links to professional info.

The Apple Cart - Graduation Announcements

applecart.rsvp

Full stack Javascript application, using Remix framework (React and Node.js). I designed and developed the entire application, including setting up auto-scaling infrastructure. Currently handling tens of thousands of visitors daily during graduation season.